Albert E. Minns, Jr., papers
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Albert E. Minns, Jr., papers
1910 - 1972
1938 - 1961
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Minns, Albert E. (Albert Edward), 1907-
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
certificates; military maps; military records; Pharmacists New York (State) Buffalo; Armed Forces Institute of Pathology (U.S.). Medical Museum; mortgages; original photographs; United States. Army. Medical Service Corps; World War, 1939-1945; scrapbooks
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
After receiving a degree from the University of Buffalo School of Pharmacy in 1926, Minns worked as a pharmacist at Allendel Pharmacy until 1941, when he entered the U.S. Army Medical Service Corps. During and after World War II (1944-1948) he served in New Guinea, the Philippines and Japan. In 1958 he was promoted to colonel and served as curator of the Medical Museum of the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology. After retiring from the army, Minns worked as a pharmacist at Roswell Park Memorial Institute.
Records pertaining to Minns' military career in the Medical Service Corps, 1941-1961,including commissions, commendations, diplomas, Bronze Star citation, Second Oak Leaf Cluster citation, clippings and photographs. Also, deeds and mortgages, 1910-1912, pertaining to property at 151 High St. in Buffalo owned by Albert Minns, Sr.
Organized into five series: I. Biographical information, 1937- 1972. II. Photo albums and scrapbooks, 1941-1951. III. Diplomas, citations and other certificates, 1945-1962. IV. Documents related to parents' house, 1910-1912. V. Miscellaneous. Chronological arrangement within series.
- Series I: Biographical Information, 1937 - 1972 (Box-folder 1.1-1.3)
  - Folder 1: Biographical summary, ca. 1972
  - Folder 2: Military service record, 1947-1961
  - Vol. 1: Military service record, ca. 1937-1948
  - Vol. 2: Military service record, ca. 1948-1958
  - Vol. 3: Military service record, ca. 1948-1962
- Series II: Photograph Albums and Scrapbooks, 1941 - 1945 (Box-folder 2.1-2.4)
  - Vol. 1: Buffalo, NY; Ft. Benning, Ga.; Cp. Gordon, Ga.; Memphis, Tenn.; May 20, 1941 - July 15, 1944
  - Vol. 2: New Guinea, Sept. 3, 1944 - Dec. 12, 1944, September 3, 1944 - December 12, 1944
  - Vol. 3: The Philippines, Dec. 15, 1944 - Aug. 18, 1945, December 15, 1944 - August 28, 1945
  - Vol. 4: Japan, Sept. 6, 1945 - Jan. 4, 1948, September 6, 1945 - January 4, 1948
  - Folder 1: Scrapbook, ca. 1942-1951
- Series III: Diplomas, Citations and Other Certificates, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Folder 2: Diplomas, Citations and Other Certificates, 1945-1962
- Series IV: Documents Related to Parents' House, 151 High St., Buffalo, 1910 - 1912 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Folder 3: Documents Related to Parents' House, 151 High St., Buffalo, 1910 - 1912
- Series V: Miscellaneous, ca. 1945-1961 (Box-folder 3.4-3.7)
  - Folder 4: Autographed photo of Gen. Douglas MacArthur, n.d.
  - Folder 5: Motor Vehicle Operator's Permit, 1950
  - Folder 6: Philippine Campaign maps, 1945
  - Folder 7: Medical Museum of Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, 1961